<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="AMW_AJC_PlaySchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<xml>
    <scene part="I">Scene I</scene>
        <play>
            <stageDirections>Before the curtain rises, Christmas chimes are heard,
            playing distinctly,---"Christmas, awake! Salute the hap-
            py morn, Whereon the Savior of mankind was born."
            At the close of the chimes a pause of 30 seconds abso-
            lute silence; after which there sounds shrill and clear a
            single stroke of a bell. The curtain rises, disclosing a
            room of a humble family of three children. "The little
            Mother" is busy about the evening meal; Nannette is
            setting the table; Annikins, on the floor, cuts pictures
            for paper dolls.</stageDirections>

            <person name="Nannette">NANNETTE.</person> <dialogue>What are the bells ringing for?
            
            <person name="Hannah">HANNAH.</person> Why, don't you know dear? They're ringing
            for the CHristmas Child---for His birthday. This is Christ-
            mas Eve!</dialogue>

            <person name="Annikins">ANNIKINS.</person> <dialogue>Is Christ Child coming here?</dialogue>

            <person name="Hannah">HANNAH.</person> <dialogue>I'm afraid not, deary. But we'll try to be happy
            just the same. We'll play "make believe" and make each
            other wonnderful presents. It's lots of fun! And write 
            letters to Daddy, and we'll ask the Christ Child to brings
            Daddy home to us, and then mother will not have to 
            works so hard down town. And we'll ask the Christ Child 
            to bring us sweet  Peaxe and Good Will. Because He is the
            Prince of Peace, and that;s what He is coming for. And
            then I s'pose we ought to pray for Democracy, 'cause
            that's what Daddy is fighting for.</dialogue>

            <page number="2">2</page>

            <person name="Nannette">NANNETTE.</person> <dialogue>What is Democracy?</dialogue>

            <person name="Hannah">HANNAH.</person> <dialogue>I'm not sure I know, little sister. It's kind of
            hard to understand. But it must be what the Christ Child
            wants every where in the world---for it  means every body
            will be good and kind to every body and they'll not be
            any poor people who can't get enough to eat, nor any un-
            kind people who scorn and hate. Just all the world will
            love each other like you and I and Annikins love one
            another. Every body will be helping to make the world
            good and pleasant for every body elseand so the Christ
            Child will come back to us again and He will be our Big
            Brother and all the people will be brothers 'cause you see
            they will all be His brothers. Come now Annikins, pit
            away your paper dollies. Supper is ready.</dialogue>
            <stageDirections>(She smoothes the child's hair, examines hands and face 
            to see that they are clean, and lifts her into a high-chair
            at the table. The others take their places and, with 
            bowed heads and folded hands, sing the grace)---
            </stageDirections>
            <prayer>God is great and God is good,
            And we thank thee for this food;
            By they hand must we be fed,
            Give us, Lord, our daily bread. Amen</prayer>

            <person name="Annikins">ANNIKINS.</person> <dialogue>Pass the sugar! <stageDirections>(correcting herself)</stageDirections> Excuse
            me sister, please pass the sugar!</dialogue>

            <person name="Hannah">HANNAH.</person> <dialogue>Oo-h Annikins! Don't take quite so much, love!
            Uncle Sam says we can't have any more sugar till next
            month!</dialogue>

            <person name="Annikins">ANNIKINS.</person> <stageDirections>(Confidently to her big sister)</stageDirections> <dialogue>you tell the
            Christmas Child I want some sugar,---hear?</dialogue> (Carol singers 
            are heard outside)
        
            <page number="3">3</page>

            <person name="Hannah">HANNAH.</person> <dialogue>Hush, child, listen. It's the carol singers!
            </dialogue>

            <person name="Carol Singers">CAROL SINGERS.</person>
            <sing>Christmas where the children are hopeful and gay,
            Christmas where old menare patient and gray,
            Christmas with peace, like a dove in its flight,
            Over brave men in the thick of the fight,
            Everywhere, everywhere, Christmas tonight!</sing>
            <stageDirections>Immediately after the carols the Sunshine Club come 
            bursting in, covered with snow. The boys wear muffllers.
            Some have ice-skates hung over their shoulders. Two
            of the boys lug in a tree all ready to set up. The girls
            have their arms full of trinkets for the tree and presents
            for their children. They are bubbling over with spirits 
            and gayly shouting,---"Merry Christmas Hannah! Mer-
            ry Christmas Nannette! Hello, Annikins! Merry
            Christmas!" Their leader gives the child a bear-hug,
            and presents her with a wonderful doll, almost as big
            as the four-year-old herself. Nannette gets a beautiful 
            red dress and a string of beads. The children clap their
            hands in glee. While dressing the tree they sing.</stageDirections>
            There's a wonderful tree a wonderful tree
            <sing>The happy children rejoice to see.
            Spreading its branches year by year
            It comes from the forest to flourish here.
            Oh this beautiful tree with its branches wide
            Is always blooming at Christmas Tide;
            And a voice is telling its boughs among
            Of the Shepherds' watch and the Angels' song;
            Of a holy Babe in the manger low---
            The beautiful story of long ago---
            When a radiant star threw its beams so wide
            To hearld the earliest Christmas Tide.</sing>
            <stageDirections>(Joining hands, and singing, they dance around the
            tree)</stageDirections>

            <page number="4">4</page>

            <person name="Hannah">HANNAH.</person> <stageDirections>(A little shyly at first)</stageDirections> <dialogue>Oh thank you! Thank
            you so much girls. What a beautiful tree! Oh, we are
            so happy---I had no idea we would have a tree!</dialogue>
        
            <person name="1st Sunshine Girl">1st SUNSHINE GIRL.</person> <stageDirections>(Hanging a small doll on the tree)</stageDirections>
            <dialogue>Here is  a baby-doll for Annikins; skates for Nannette.
            And here, little Mother, is a gay peasant-kerchief and a
            picture storybook for you. I know you'll read the stories
            to the rest. Hannah never keeps anything all for herself!</dialogue>
        
            <person name="Hannah">HANNAH.</person> <stageDirections>(Somewhat embarrassed)</stageDirections> <dialogue>Oh girls, I---I can't
            tell you how much---Oh, I mean you are so good and
            kind---I just don't know how to thank you.</dialogue>
        
            <person name="1st Sunshine Girl">1st SUNSHINE GIRL.</person> <dialogue>Oh don't thank us at all, just thank 
            the Christ Child!</dialogue>
        
            <person name="2nd Sunshine Girl">2nd SUNSHINE GIRL.</person> <dialogue>All who love the Christ Child are
            trying to make little children happy tonight, don't you
            know? We don't want a single child to be forgotten. His
            love will warm and cheer the loneliest child on earth.</dialogue>
        
            <person name="Hannah">HANNAH.</person> <stageDirections>(Thoughtfully)</stageDirections> <dialogue>Yes. All for the Christ Child
            who was born tonight. To love Him is to love all little children.</dialogue>
        
            <person name="Sunshine Girls">SUNSHINE GIRLS.</person> <stageDirections>(Putting on their wraps, waving Mer-
            ry Christmas to all; shaking hands affectionately with
            Hannah).</stageDirections> <dialogue>Good night everybody! Be good children!
            Good night,---good night!</dialogue>
        
            <person name="The Children">THE CHILDREN.</person> <dialogue>Good night! Merry Christmas!</dialogue>
        
            <person name="Annikins">ANNIKINS.</person> <stageDirections>(Piping up)</stageDirections> <dialogue>Au revoir-au revoir!</dialogue> <stageDirections>(Exit S.S.
            Club laughing and throwing kisses. A pause)</stageDirections>

            <person name="Nannette">NANNETTE.</person> <dialogue>What a wonderful tree!</dialogue> <stageDirections>(They examine the 
            presents)</stageDirections>

            <page number="5">5</page>

            <person name="Hannah">HANNAH.</person> <stageDirections>(Bustling to hide her emotion)</stageDirections> Come now
            <stageDirections>(Takes Annikins by the hand).</stageDirections> <dialogue>The Christ Child has sent
            us perfectly lovely friends and I am so glad you have
            your Christmas tree after all! Kneel down children. An-
            nikins, put your hands together.</dialogue> <stageDirections>(They all kneel and re-
            peat a prayer)</stageDirections>
            <prayer>Oh holy Child of Bethlehem!
            Descend to us we pray;
            Cast our sin and enter in,
            Be born in us today.
            We hear the Christmas angels
            The great glad tidings tell;
            Oh, come to us---Abide with us,
            Our Lord, Emanuel.</prayer>
            <stageDirections>(During the prayer the stage is gradually darkened, so 
            that the children are no longer visible)</stageDirections>
        </play>
</xml>
    